RG 002:025, Education Committee
Connecticut State Library
Education Committee records
1972-2007
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. General Assembly. Joint Standing Committee on Education
22 cubic feet
Subjects covered include adult literacy, bilingual education, higher education, school construction, school integration, school equalization, special education, teacher and school administrator shortage.
RG002_025_EDU
Multiple
Scope and Content
Subjects covered include adult literacy, bilingual education, higher education, school construction, school integration, school equalization, special education, teacher and school administrator shortage. Records include meeting material, background material and legislative material.
Arrangement
Arranged by accessions.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Joint Standing Committee on Education
Subjects:
Connecticut. General Assembly. Joint Standing Committee on Education -- Records and correspondence; Education and state -- Connecticut; Education, Bilingual -- Connecticut; Education, Higher -- Connecticut; Education -- Law and legislation -- Connecticut; Educational equalization -- Connecticut; English language -- Study and teaching -- Connecticut -- Foreign speakers; Functional literacy -- Connecticut; Public universities and colleges -- Connecticut; School administrators -- Supply and demand -- Connecticut; School construction contracts -- Connecticut; School integration -- Connecticut; Segregation in education -- Connecticut; Special education -- Connecticut; Teachers -- Supply and demand -- Connecticut; Vocational education -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Agendas; Membership lists; Minutes; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Accession T003181, 1973-1975
  - Minutes and attendance, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Certification evaluation hearing, 1971 March 19 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum hearings, 1973 March 22, 26 (Box 1)
  - Finance and education, 1973 April 18 (Box 1)
  - Governance regionalization hearing, 1973 February 28 (Box 1)
  - Finance Study Commission, 1973 December - 1975 January (Box 2)
  - Hearings, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Library, 1973 February 15 (Box 2)
    - Negotiations tenure, 1973 March 15 (Box 2)
    - Petitioned bills, 1973 April 2 (Box 2)
    - School construction, public and private, 1973 March 5 (Box 2)
    - School transportation, 1973 March 5 (Box 2)
    - Special Education, 1973 March 12 (Box 2)
    - State aid - public and private schools, 1973 March 8 (Box 2)
- Accession T001602, 1976-1990
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1976 February-March (Box 3)
  - Report on bills favorable acted upon, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1977 January-December (Box 3)
  - Meeting minutes of Interim Study Committee, Areas# 1-5, 1977 September - 1978 January (Box 3)
  - Membership, staff schedules, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, memos, reports, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1978 January - April (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Meeting minutes and related documents of subcommittees #1-6, 1979 June - 1980 February (Box 4)
  - Meeting minutes of ad hoc commission on inter-district cooperation and racial imbalance, 1980 November - February (Box 4)
  - Horton-Meskill, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Transcript, 1979 January 25 (Box 4)
    - Documents (Box 4)
  - Membership, schedules, list of bills, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1980 January-March (Box 4)
  - Meeting minutes of Special Education Placement Study Committee, 1980 September - December (Box 4)
  - meeting minutes of School Construction Priority Listing Committee, 1980 July 16 (Box 4)
  - Subcommittee #5 Higher Education, 1980 June 5 (Box 4)
  - Membership, staff, schedules, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Meeting minutes of Committee to Study Special Education Placements, 1981 January - 1982 February (Box 4)
  - Meeting minutes of School Construction, Priority Listing Sub-Committee #3, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Membership, schedules, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Bill listings and miscellaneous memos, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1982 January-May (Box 5)
  - Meeting minutes - Special Education Placements, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Meeting minutes - Employment of Handicapped Adults, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Meeting minutes - Subcommittees #1-3 and School Construction Priority Listing, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Minutes of joint meeting with Planning and Development committee, 1982 January 25 (Box 5)
  - Meeting transcripts, 1982 January 27-29 (Box 5)
  - Membership, staff, listing of bills, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1983 January - June (Box 5)
  - Meeting minutes - Employment of Handicapped Adults, 1983 June - 1984 February (Box 5)
  - Meeting minutes - Commission on Special Education, 1983 January - 1984 February (Box 5)
  - Meeting minutes - Other special committees, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    - Binding Arbitration Awards, 1983 October - 1984 January (Box 5)
    - Day Care Licensing, 1983 September - October (Box 5)
    - School Construction Priority Listing, 1983 January (Box 5)
    - Teachers Bargaining Unit, 1983 November (Box 5)
    - Grants to Public Libraries, 1983 December (Box 5)
  - Meeting transcripts, 1983 November 13, 15 (Box 5)
  - Membership, schedules, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Bills - procedures, listing, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1984 February-April (Box 6)
  - Meeting minutes and related documents - Special Education, 1984 January - September (Box 6)
  - Panel discussion at New Haven transcript, 1984 May 11 (Box 6)
  - Membership, staff, schedules, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Bill record, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Meeting minutes of special committees, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
    - Special Education, 1985 August - 1986 January (Box 6)
    - School Construction Priority Listing, 1985 (Box 6)
    - University of Connecticut / Torrington Higher Education, 1985 July 8 (Box 6)
  - Meeting transcripts full committee, 1985 January 7, 31 (Box 6)
  - Workshop on teachers salary (Box 6)
    - Transcripts, 1985 December 16 (Box 6)
    - Hearing testimony, 1985 December 16 (Box 6)
    - Department of Education proposal, 1985 December 15 (Box 6)
    - Background documents (Box 6)
  - Special Education, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Standing Committee annual report, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Background material (Box 6)
  - School Construction, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Priority listing by State Board of Education, 1985 December 12 (Box 6)
  - Student Financial Aid, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Background material (Box 6)
  - Membership, list of bills, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Meeting minutes of full committee, 1986 (Box 6)
  - School construction - priority lists, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous documents re public hearings, special subcommittees, etc., 1990 (Box 6)
- Accession 1985-023, 1978-1983
  - Appointment letters (Box 1)
  - Interim Education Committee (Box 1)
  - Education block grant (Box 1)
  - College purchases, Special Act 80-23 (Box 1)
  - State colleges (Box 1)
  - Interim Subcommittee #1-3 (Box 1)
  - Meeting minutes (Box 1)
  - Education Research File (Box 1)
  - OLR vocational study (Box 1)
  - Commission to study Special Education Placements (Box 2)
  - Mandates (Box 2)
  - School Construction (Box 2)
  - Special Education Commission (Box 2)
  - Guaranteed Tax Base (GTB) Error (Box 3)
  - GTB, Joint Committee on Review of (Box 3)
  - Education Equity Study Commission (Box 3)
  - Department of Education Budget (Box 3)
  - Teacher Shortage (Box 3)
  - Growing up at risk in CT (Box 3)
  - Higher Education: Research files (Box 3)
  - Assessment of sales ratio study (Box 3)
  - Master plan for vocational and career education (Box 3)
  - Teacher retirement (Box 3)
  - Special education (Box 3)
  - Higher education (Box 3)
  - Proposed bills (Box 3)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 3)
  - New GTB formula (Box 4)
  - Student statistics (Box 4)
  - Citizens for old GTB formula (Box 4)
  - CT School Finance Advisory Panel (Box 4)
  - School Finance in CT: Preliminary Analysis (Box 4)
  - Special Education Placement (Box 4)
  - Proprietary Schools (Box 5)
  - Technical College Response to Questionnaire (Box 5)
  - Community College Response to Questionnaire (Box 5)
  - Commission to Study Violence in Sporting Events (Box 5)
  - Proficiency Testing (Box 5)
  - Relationship of Sales Assessment Ratio Study to GTB (Box 6)
  - Equalization Bill Proposals (Box 6)
  - Raised Bill #7586 (Box 6)
  - First Draft, Summary, Amendments, Final Version (Box 6)
  - OLR Equalization Report (Box 6)
  - OLR Joint Favorable Report (Box 6)
  - Horton vs. Meskill, Analysis and Brief (Box 6)
  - Education Finance (Box 6)
  - OLR Report on School Financial Aid in USA (Box 6)
  - School Equalization Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Statistical Data (Box 6)
  - Computer printouts (GTB Formula) (Box 7)
  - Amendments to Equity Proposition (Box 7)
  - Equity: Statute Info (Box 7)
  - Equity: Proposal (Box 7)
  - Due Process Amendment (Box 7)
  - Transportation (Box 7)
  - Responsibilities of State and Local Districts (Box 7)
  - Finance Materials (Box 7)
  - Adult Education (Box 8)
  - Alcohol, State Council on (Box 8)
  - Arts, Commission on the (Box 8)
  - Allen: Legislative Proposal (Box 8)
  - Alternative Schools (Box 8)
  - Assessment Education (Box 8)
  - Bilingual Education (Box 8)
  - CT Association of Board of Education (Box 8)
  - CPTV and CATV (Box 8)
  - CT Education Association (Box 8)
  - Compensatory Education (Box 8)
  - Compensatory Plan for Elementary and Secondary Schools (Box 8)
  - CT Economy (Box 8)
  - Construction: School Buildings (Box 8)
  - Consumer Education (Box 8)
  - Curriculum (Box 8)
  - Data Acquisition Plan (Box 9)
  - Day Care and Early Education (Box 9)
  - Department of Education – Federal (Box 9)
  - Drivers Education (Box 9)
  - Simulation and Multiple Care Driving Range Info (Box 9)
  - Teachers Guide to Environmental Education (Box 9)
  - Enrollment Statistics (Box 9)
  - Shanti School (Box 9)
  - Hansen Commission Reports (Box 9)
  - School Health and Welfare Services (Box 9)
  - Human Services (Box 10)
  - Inter-district Cooperation (Box 10)
  - Legal Information (Box 10)
  - Librarians (Box 10)
  - Paraprofessionals (Box 10)
  - Re-codification (Box 10)
  - Proficiency Test (Box 10)
  - Regulations and Resolutions (Box 10)
  - Disapproval Notices (Box 10)
  - Racial Imbalance (Box 10)
  - OLR Reports on Desegregation (Box 10)
  - School Bus Safety (Box 11)
  - School Day – School Year (Box 11)
  - School Lunch (Box 11)
  - School Safety/Violence (Box 11)
  - Teacher Testing (Box 11)
  - Testing (Box 11)
  - Vocational and Career Education (Box 11)
  - Vocational and Career Education (Box 12)
  - Inter-district Vocational Education (Box 12)
  - Program Review (Vocational Education) (Box 12)
  - Vocational: Rehabilitation (Box 12)
  - Welfare (Box 12)
  - Women (Box 12)
  - Higher Education: Accreditation (Box 13)
  - Higher Education: Alternative (Box 13)
  - Higher Education Centers (Box 13)
  - Higher Education: Disadvantages Minorities and Women (Box 13)
  - Commission for Higher Education (Box 13)
  - Community Colleges (Box 13)
  - Technical Colleges (Box 13)
  - Graduate (Box 13)
  - Housing (Box 13)
  - UCONN Health Center (Box 14)
  - Veterinary Medicine (Box 14)
  - Tufts Veterinary Medicine Program (Box 14)
  - MBA at Stamford (Box 14)
  - Board of Higher Education (BHE): Workshops (Box 14)
  - Board of Higher Education (BHE): Board of Trustees (Box 14)
  - Board of Higher Education (BHE): Budget (Box 14)
  - Board of Higher Education (BHE): General Info (Box 14)
  - Board of Higher Education (BHE): Guidelines (Box 14)
  - Board of Higher Education (BHE): Proposals (Box 14)
  - Board of Higher Education (BHE): Reports (Box 14)
- Accession 1998-008A, 1987-1989
  - Meeting minutes, 1987-1989; 3 volumes in shared box (Box 1)
- Accession 1998-008B, 1987-1989
  - Interim Task Forces meeting minutes, 1987-1989; 1 volume in shared box (Box 1)
- Accession 1998-008C, 1979, 1984
  - School Equalization Subcommittee, 2 folders in shared box (Box 1)
    - Working papers, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Horton v. Meskill, 1984 (Box 1)
- Accession 1999-023, 1982-1985
  - Investigation of GTB error, 1982-1985 (Box 1)
- Accession 1999-050, 1976, 1983
  - Bill record, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Bill record, 1983 (Box 1)
- Accession 1999-093, 1991-1992
  - Bill book, 1991 (Box 1)
  - CT Student Assessment Program, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Bill book, 1992 (Box 1)
- Accession 2007-048, 1990-2002
  - Meeting notices, agendas, minutes, 1990-1995 (Box 1)
  - Meeting notices, agendas, minutes, 1996-2000 (Box 2)
  - Meeting notices, agendas, minutes, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Education Week covers, 1998-2002 (Box 3)
- Accession 2008-009, 1991-2003
  - Adult Literacy Task Force, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - Background material, 1996; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Meetings, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - Adult Literacy Symposium, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Air quality in elementary schools, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Bilingual Study Group, 1996-1998; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
  - Educational Improvement Panel (Sheff v. O'Neill), 1996; 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Informational forum, 2002 February 13 (Box 1)
  - Mastery Testing Program, 189-1995; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Reports (Box 1)
    - Charter schools, 1997-1998, undated (Box 1)
    - Governors' initiatives, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Hull-Harper report, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Implementation of teacher training, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Joint Committee on Educational Technology, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994-2001; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous reports from the Dept. of Education, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Native language subject matter assessment instruments, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Pre-engineering program for vocational-technical schools, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Priority school district grants for extending school building hours program, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
    - Progress in reducing racial, ethnic, and economic isolation, 2003; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Regional planning for educational quality and diversity, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Special education in Connecticut, 1991-1992, 1995-1997, 2001; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Teacher negotiation act, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Special Education Working Group, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Teacher and School Administrator Shortage and Minority Recruitment, Commission on, 2000-2001; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Vocational-Technical Study Group, 1997-1998; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Legislative material (Box 2)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning impartial arbitrator selection, 1990 (Box 2)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning the sale of competitive foods in schools, 1992 (Box 2)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning reports of child abuse b a certified school employee, 1993 (Box 2)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning early intervention services for infants and toddlers and their families, 1995 (Box 2)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning school construction grants, 1995 (Box 3)
    - State Board of Education miscellaneous regulations, 1995 (Box 3)
    - State Board of Accountancy regulation concerning continuing education and the requirements for renewal of a certified public accountant or a public accountant license, 1995 (Box 3)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning personal data systems, 1997; 2 copies (Box 3)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning issuance of the state high school diploma, 1997; 2 copies (Box 3)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning organization description, 1997; 2 copies (Box 3)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning the youth service bureau grant program, 1997 (Box 3)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning the youth service bureau grant program, 1998 (Box 3)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning standards and procedures for the approval of Connecticut educator preparation programs, 1998 (Box 3)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning state educator certificates, permits & authorizations, 1998 (Box 3)
    - State Board of Education regulations concerning state educator certificates, permits & authorizations, 2003 (Box 3)
- Accession 2014-027, 1972-2007
  - Appointments and resolutions for State Colleges Board of Trustees, 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bill book, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 2 block grant, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Drug free schools block grant, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Education finance, 1978-1979, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Independent living, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - School Construction Priority List Subcommittee, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - School Construction Priority List Subcommittee, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sheff v. O'Neill informatin forum, 2007 June 20, July 12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Special Education Cost Committee minutes, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Standing Committee on Special Education, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Votes, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)